What up guys? Welcome to Magpie.
Uh so right now we're going to be
waiting on the students to show up and
then once we have enough people we're
just going to start chatting. We're
going to keep it casual and we're just
going to answer questions. They've
already been through a whole day of
school at this point. [music] They're
taking time out of their after hours to
come speak with us. So uh we're going to
keep it light. Guys, come on. Have a
seat. Is it okay with you guys if we
wait just a few more minutes to make
sure that we have some stragglers? Is
that all right? Cool. Thank you guys
[music] so much. Oh by the way, if you
guys are hungry I brought snacks from my
bakery. And if you pretend to be shy I
will get angry at you. Just dig your
Just stick your hands in and start
grabbing food. And I brought enough for
you to have here and also some to take
home to your parents or your friends.
Firstly, thank you so much for taking
time out of your off hours [music] to
come speak with me. And as such, in the
interest of keeping things short, I'm
going to do away with all the fancy and
the serious. So, I'm Caden Skow, I cook
in Jinjiang and I'm here to answer your
questions. Anything
>> [music]
>> that you have on your minds, whether it
be about my industry, not about my
industry, whatever you're thinking
about, whatever you're studying,
whatever you're working on, or whatever
your plans might be. Anything [music] is
uh available as a topic of discussion.
So, is there anybody who would like to
start us off?
The most important thing to become a
chef?
>> [music]
>> Thank you so much for your question.
That's pretty clean. Uh so in my
opinion, cuz I don't represent every
cook, but I do represent a good portion
of cooks, I believe that there are four
key factors.
>> [music]
>> Endurance is one of them. And not just
physical endurance,
uh the ability to endure failure
repeatedly [music] and boredom. Cuz most
of the job is boring. 99% of it is just
wiping and cleaning. It's only exciting
less than 1% of the time. Like [music]
painting, right? Second of all is I
think a belief system. So, you need to
have beliefs. It can be local produce.
[music] It can be traditional cuisine.
It can be traditional techniques. It can
be modernist above all else creativity.
But, you [music] need to have a belief
system whether it be right or wrong, it
cannot be shaken or moved.
Or it's not a belief. It's just an
understanding. And violence. Cooks need
to have an understanding and
appreciation [music]
for and the ability to to use violence
because cooking is [music] violent. To
slice things, to slap things, to
tenderize things, to put things in pans,
to get burned and get cut, get scraped
[music] and get pushed by your
colleagues and yelled at and pushed up
against the lock in a walk in like by
someone stronger than you and angrier
than you. Violence will happen and the
ability to stomach it and understand
that in [music] a systematic and
controlled environment is a learning
opportunity. It's not something to run
away from. And fourth,
candor. Candor is very important.
[music] Absolute honesty. So, honesty is
provoked. It's reactive. So, for you to
be honest with me, I must ask you a
question first. Candor, for lack of a
better description, is [music] the
ability to speak unprovoked with
honesty.
Right? So, if you cook candidly, then
you know that you will never misname a
dish or to misrepresent technique
[music] or to go out of your way to make
something feel like something it's not
like certain Michelin restaurants.
[music] This is an essence of dairy.
Like that's milk, bro.
An essence of dairy is milk, man. Right?
So, that's my opinion. Have I answered
your question? Good. Thank you so much.
Anything else?
>> What is the three red biggest red flags
in your cooking career?
>> Let me make sure that I understand your
question. [music] So, are you asking me
what I consider to be red flags in
potential colleagues and in other cooks?
>> Yeah.
>> Perfect. I think [music] that if you
can't tell me what you've made in one
sentence or less, you're not making
food. You're making an experiment in
arrogance. Like, we're all very
different, but the things that taste
good are the same. Hot, salty, fatty,
and fast.
McDonald's tastes good to everybody,
right? Let's be honest. Oh my god,
McDonald's is amazing. But if he goes
like, uh this is, like I said, a
reduction or an essence of on a bed of
and this is my experiment in, that's a
red flag to me. You're not making good
food, you just need someone [music] to
talk at, right? Second red flag is
people who take failure too seriously.
People [music] who think that failure in
any regard is
personal, right? It's it's it's an
excuse to stop rather than excuse to
push harder. That's a red flag to me cuz
you can't count on that person. And
[music] three, people who answer
questions you never asked. That's my
biggest red flag. Hey, how long for that
steak? Oh, it's doing okay. My oven just
got hot, so yeah, pretty soon. So, how
long? You know, like this is a pretty
thick piece of steak, so it's it's it's
it's it's a kind of a difficult cook.
So, how long? We're actually just
started resting a little while ago, so I
should be able to get it to you soon.
Brother, if you don't tell me in minutes
how long I'm going to come over there
and choke you with a spatula, right? So,
these are all very big red flags to me,
right? The ability to answer quickly,
move decisively, and be honest with
yourself.
>> [music]
>> And take punches to the chin and then
get up afterwards. If you fail at these
things, red flags.
>> [music]
>> Um anything from this side of the room?
>> What forced you to become a video
creator?
>> Nothing forced me.
Force is a very strong word. I use it
very [music] seldom.
I'm not necessarily passionate either,
but that does kind of perfectly answer
your question. So, um because [music]
you are obviously a very smart man,
um
No, genuinely. I view you as most likely
smart. And the reason is because you're
going to the school, you [music] make
full sentences, you're articulate. But a
lot of the times you're using
too much seasoning [music]
for what is the simple question of what
made you want to make videos.
Right? So, what forced you? What's
passionate? This is called redundancy in
speech, and that's part of the reason I
started making content because [music] I
was sick of people who have too much
redundancy in speech. So, there used to
be an MIT professor. Unfortunately, he
passed away a few years ago. He's one of
my favorite speakers. And one of the my
favorite things [music] he ever said, he
would start the lecture with, "You as a
person will be judged firstly by how you
speak, secondly by how well you write,
and lastly by the quality of your
thoughts."
Right? So, speech is very important and
I thought that I arrogantly could make
some suggestions as to how to [music]
communicate under the auspices of
teaching how to cook at the same time. I
don't know. Did I answer your question?
>> I mean, why would you want to be a video
creator?
>> I want to communicate, but the job is
being a creator. Cuz I In the same way
that I want to cook and the job is being
a chef.
There's a difference. You want to be
smart, but the job is going to school.
Right? People tell us that we should
enjoy the job. It's not true. You can
hate the job, but you still have a
purpose that you want to be at. Like I
said, you guys want to know more, but
I'm sure this is the job for now.
>> I'm wondering what is the
>> have to stand up. It's okay. It's not
that kind of meeting.
>> I'm wondering what is the most delicious
food you have
you have ever tried.
>> That I've ever tried? It depends on what
part of my life I was in. But uh one of
my recurring favorites as a dish is uh
pain au chocolat. It's one of the few
things that my dad would [music] make
with me instead of for me or next to me.
He would actually let me help. It's one
of my favorite memories. Yeah?
>> What about the year 18?
>> Pick a year and I'll give you an answer.
>> Uh
18.
>> When I was 18, that's a very good
question. When I was 18, I liked [music]
a full roast chicken in a Paris-Brest.
So, every few hundred meters of France,
you can get like a poulet rôti, which is
just a roast chicken, as well as [music]
there's always going to be another
pastry shop somewhere around the corner
that sells the Paris-Brest, which is
just a round pâte à choux and in the
inside is uh usually a crème diplomate,
which is a crème pâtissière cream mixed
with uh praliné and mixed with a little
bit of whipped cream.
>> [music]
>> Delicious.
>> All right. Would you like the more
boring one for students or the more
entertaining one? Like because one is
financial and one is about life.
>> I want the one that you would like to
ask.
>> So, if ever we have
something that we want to do, but it's
not really the best option for the
future, then
how do you suppose that we would tackle
that problem?
Do we incorporate our interest into the
jobs that we would want to do?
>> The answer is
try to find a balance and see if you can
[music] push forward while being okay
with melding your interests into your
finances, but that's the boring answer
that everybody gives. Would you like my
answer now?
The only reason you're asking that
question is because you're afraid to
piss somebody off.
If you spend the first half of your life
impressing
and catering
to a pair of people who have your best
interests at heart, I have no doubt, but
they will leave [music] you one day and
then you will be left alone on this
planet for the next half of your life.
Are you [music] okay with the math on
that? Because their job is to protect
you and help you.
You're an investment project.
You're like a property that your parents
invested in. They don't know if they're
going to make a profit on this and it's
okay. It's like they bought a holiday
home. This this child of theirs, you.
Right? They don't know if the land's
going to go up, down, sideways, in
circles, or tank. Their expectations of
you are their best efforts at trying
to minimize losses at the very least and
maybe maximize [music]
profits. But you are not a project, you
are a person. And that investment
project is going to be all yours after
your two big investors, your parents,
one day take their exit from this
project. So, there's no [music] perfect
answer, but that is the math that you
have to do. In the second half of your
life,
who are you going to be sorry for? Cuz
they're not going to be around. I did
the math on that. Like as a personal
experience, my dad I had this
conversation with him one day. I'm like,
"Dad, are you going to be pissed off if
I become a cook?" And he's like, "Yeah,
of course." I'm like, "Okay, well then
should I not?" And he's like, "Why?
[music] Are you weak-willed? Are you
weak-wristed? I'm not going to be around
forever, but you can't stop me from
being pissed off. I don't like it. Don't
expect me to like it, but I'm not going
to stop you. Go. It's your dream. You
can't expect them to like the [music]
decisions they don't like."
I'm sorry if that was a little bit
tough, but have I answered your
question?
>> Uh yes, it
>> Perfect.
>> And I really like the direct how direct
you are.
>> Anybody else?
>> Simple question.
>> Only if it's simple. I'm kidding. Go for
it.
>> What's your favorite dish and why?
>> My favorite dish
altogether?
>> The Chinese [music] one.
>> In the generic
branch of Chinese food, [music] these
two words.
Right now, I'm kind of obsessed with
Northwestern food. I can't single it
down to a dish right now, but the region
would be Northwestern at this moment.
And the why is because it [music] is
most low-key international.
Because Northwestern food was inspired
by,
you know,
the Silk Road, by the Mongol Empire,
right? By spices coming in from
Afghanistan, from India. So, I'm
obsessed with where the spices came
from, how they transmuted into current
dishes. Like, for example, alu rowar.
You ever heard of this rowar? Like,
Beijing fried meatballs?
Perfect. That's Persian koftas. It
originated as Persian food.
Yeah, so that's why I'm obsessed with
it. Like, as you eat a simple food, you
can think back into huh, how, why. One
of the first written recipes
uh that we still have today was a
meatball recipe most likely translated
by a
Semuren. So, uh it was a a rank of
ethnic Chinese person at the time during
the Yuan Dynasty.
Uh and it was translated from a Turkish
recipe by way of a Persian for a Chinese
[music] cook in the court in Dadu.
Yeah, it's crazy, right?
>> Why do you want to be a chef?
>> Why I want to be a chef? Currently or
why did I start being a chef? Those two
answers are very different.
Which one?
>> I think just why you are.
>> Right now, it's because I like labor.
I enjoy labor. I enjoy laboring. I enjoy
the feeling of my hard work ending, and
being able to define my own terms.
That's one. And two,
>> [music]
>> being a cook is one of those rare things
that inspires pretty lateral
conversation. If I was a professor, you
guys would think, "Oh, this is going to
be boring."
Right? "Oh, he's from some some
university. He's here to talk about some
something that I don't care about." But
you're like, "Oh, this guy's a cook.
Cool, let's talk about food." Cuz who
doesn't talk about food?
Right? It's a good starting to a
communication.
Wow, you guys Oh, you know, most of it
got in your mouth. That's good.
I'm glad you enjoy it, man. Uh it's the
work of my baker. I'm sure I'll let him
know that you guys liked it. By the way,
guys, I'm sorry if I didn't make this
clear earlier, but uh let me reiterate,
it doesn't have to be about my industry.
It can be about anything.
Yeah, please.
What Which country am I from?
I'm from here. I'm from China.
>> You just say English. It's very
>> It's okay, take [music] your take your
time, brother.
>> American.
>> That's fine. That's fine.
Uh I'll take it as a compliment. Are you
asking me why I sound like this?
Oh, okay. I got lucky. I just got lucky.
I enjoyed languages, and I was uh lucky
enough to be blessed with people who
were willing to teach me. So, if you
don't like languages, you're not going
to learn languages well. I try my best
to be at least polite in as many
languages as I can be, cuz I like them.
They're fun. Languages are cool. There's
nothing more disarming than being able
[music] to speak a language. Yeah, you
can save a lot of money. You can travel
to many places.
>> Uh
I'd like to go back to the previous
topic I had earlier. Well, my favorite
subject in high school was science.
However, I There's a really good
It's just that I'm I'm torn between
electronic
engineering and English literature.
>> Okay. Um would you mind talking a little
bit more about
your criteria? Uh for example, why you
would choose [music] English literature
instead
of electronic communications and
engineering?
>> Out of pure spite.
>> Out of pure spite. So, your parents want
you to take ECE.
>> I'm not so sure about that, but from the
looks of it, probably they would prefer
me to take ECE.
>> So, can I understand this to mean that
you're getting the vibes
>> [music]
>> that your parents have a preference, but
out of pure parental respect for you,
they're
>> I'm going
>> respecting your decision.
>> Maybe I'll I'll rephrase the question.
What's your take on English literature?
Like, your opinion on English
literature.
>> My opinion on [music] English literature
is that as a field of study,
it's very marginalized.
Your eventual
sources of income are spurious, at best.
If you genuinely want to learn lit
because you love lit, then learn lit.
You don't have [music] to go to school
for it. Books are always available to
you.
And literature professors have nothing
better to do than talk to people who are
interested in literature. For example,
you right now [music]
can go on the internet and search up a
collection of very important papers and
treatises and theses on whatever it is
that you find [music] interesting. And
when you look at who wrote that, you
literally can look for his email or his
phone number, and if you call him, he
will explode with excitement because
people with PhDs are lonely.
>> [laughter]
>> So, you can if the most exciting thing,
the most generous, gracious, majestic,
exciting thing you can do for someone
who's good at what they do,
is show an interest. [music] So, if
generally you want to do lit because you
like lit, I wouldn't waste time and
money on it. But that's my opinion.
>> [music]
>> Right? I would spend my time on
something that might be able to secure
an income that I don't hate.
Because literature is [music] free.
>> Is there something some dumb things you
have done where you have learning
cooking?
>> Sure. From my kneecap down to my ankle
on this leg was gone at some point. The
entire [music] skin from here all the
way down to here, gone.
This corner of my head, gone. [music]
The patch of skin on my hand here, gone.
Um I've dislocated my shoulder once in
the kitchen. Um yeah. Lots of dumb
things. Lots of injuries. [music]
Cooking can be a safe job, but usually
it's made unsafe by
the people who cook. Dumb boys.
I got this, chef. And I so did not got
this.
>> [laughter]
>> I had I I had that I had it 0%.
I did not got it at all.
>> So any dumb that you think that you like
you make a big fault or you think that
you want to apologize for any others?
>> Sure. Yeah. A not insignificant part of
my career was spent being angry, and I
know [music] that I caused a lot of
anxiety for some colleagues.
Uh and I regret it immeasurably. It just
wasn't worth it.
It wasn't worth [music] it. Cuz there's
a period of time where every cook wants
to have his Michelin stars.
Have you ever heard the term like have
his flowers?
>> [music]
>> To have your flowers means for for you
to have your your like
your accolades, for people to finally
recognize you [music] and give you your
just due and your credit for being
awesome. Have your flowers. I'm giving
you
right? Your wreath.
Or your bouquet. Um I wanted my flowers,
and I would not stop [music] at anything
to get them.
And then I realized that I don't really
like flowers. It just wasn't worth it.
It wasn't worth the anguish [music] and
the pain. Cuz it's not an easy job. And
the worst part is I spent all day with
my colleagues
marching in perfect harmony to the beat
of one
drum. Name was chef.
Whatever Chef said, you said "Oui,
Chef." or "Non, Chef." or
"Immédiatement."
And you would march to this temperature
every single day.
And you would do [music] this. You would
try to work while this noise happens.
And it doesn't matter how much you want
to tear your hair out and how annoying
it is. It gets louder and louder and
people are still hungry and the tickets
still come in and you've burned your
hand and the pots are heavy and the
kitchen gets hot and the job is hard but
people still want to eat.
And instead of taking it out
on the people you don't know who caused
you [music] your pain, your guests, all
you can do is take it out on your
colleagues who actually care about you.
And then one day I realized it wasn't
worth it. [music] So, that's something I
regret, caring too much
at the cost of my colleagues. Have I
answered your question? Okay, thank you
so much.
>> How and why can you be so positive? And,
you know, even in the whole sharing, you
know, you're really positive. And then
the share sharing is really [music]
inspiring as well.
You know, how can you stay so positive?
That's the first question. Second
question, you know, a little bit more
personal. When's the last time that you
cried? And for what?
>> I last time I cried was about a week
ago.
I just missed my dad. Just all of a
sudden, I saw something that reminded me
of my dad and I haven't thought about
him in a while. Cuz it's my personal
opinion that in in in English culture,
well, in anybody's culture, but
everybody has different words for it.
[music] But in English you would say
it'll get better.
Right? Or in Chinese you would say
"一切都会好的."
"一切都会好的." And I don't believe that. I
believe that if there's ever a day where
my dad doesn't make me sad, [music]
that makes me a bad son. But that's my
personal opinion. I don't think there's
ever going to be a day
where talking about my dad is going to
not feel poor. So, yeah, about a week
ago. I was just I saw an old Lexus LS
400 um
and it reminded me of my dad and I had
to pull over and think about it for a
second.
Which is
>> [music]
>> a beautiful thing to ask someone. Thank
you for that. Um the first part, how can
I remain positive? I think I think it's
because I don't really have a frame of
reference. I don't know what negativity
sounds like in regards to my career or
this conversation. Don't be a cook.
Don't be a cook. Don't be a cook. That
might be negative, but that's also good
advice. All right?
Like I said, candor above all else. This
would be candor. Like I I I I haven't a
reason nor am I looking for a reason
[music] to not tell you this. So,
whatever you ask me, I answer. I
apologize if I've been too loquacious or
verbose.
Uh
but I'm trying my best to be succinct.
Yeah?
Thank you for your question, brother.
Have I answered? Awesome. Thank you.
Please.
>> I wanted to ask, like, when you said you
about your injuries, how did you get
them?
>> Sure. Uh from my knee to my ankle on my
left foot, I was pushing so we were
busy.
About a walkway
is meant to be able to accommodate two
cooks back-to-back working at our
respective counters.
There was a fryer here and we were
having a busy service and we [music]
were two hands down and chef said, "I
need you to drop the fryer." Drop the
fryer means switch the oil out. Someone
had dropped something in the fryer oil
that made it black and it was screwing
up the food.
Now, you usually drop the fryer after a
service when no one's busy anymore. And
you drop the fryer by taking a
skateboard and putting a big pot on it
and pushing
the pot over to a valve that opens up.
Hot oil pours in through a filter
[music] and then you push the hot oil
out on the ground, nice and safe.
But we were busy in the middle of
service, so there was eight bodies in
the kitchen. So, we went over there,
dropped the fryer, but we couldn't push
it cuz everyone was in the way. There
was literally no room.
So, we being dumb boys were like, "All
right, we'll go over the top."
Which means that you pick it up, hold it
on your shoulders, and push it up. Now,
as you're walking, this guy, his hands
weren't as thick as [music] cuz he had
just started cooking not too long ago
and he couldn't handle the heat, but he
was too proud to say anything.
So, he just let go of it on me. It fell,
hot [music] oil all over
the floor. And then as I turned around,
I slipped, fell into the hot oil, so I
had a burn all the way down my my knee.
And my hand. And [music] then chef tried
to grab me out of it, so he grabs me by
the knee and pulls me away from the oil,
but it just took the skin off, so I look
like a turkey. I got to look like
[music] a glazed ham, essentially.
Yeah. But I had to finish service, so we
grabbed a couple [music] clean rags,
wrapped it around my leg, tied it off
with some cling film so saran wrap, and
we finished up service and they sent me
away. Always finish service.
Unless you're missing an arm or a leg,
it's not an excuse to skip the blind. Of
course, that's bad advice. If you get
injured, go to the freaking hospital.
But because I was a boy,
I'm a manly manly man and this doesn't
hurt at all. Ow ow ow ow ow ow ow
>> We might have to wrap it up here because
like the library is about to close and
then I think you guys have asked
[snorts] enough questions about it. So,
any last comments or anything else you
want to you want to say before you go?
>> Come to the restaurant, but it's
probably not going [music] to be me
cooking. It's probably going to be my
colleagues.
Uh but I'm a ginger.
Yeah. You should be able to find the
address to our restaurant somewhere.
>> The name of the name of the restaurant?
>> In English, it's called Magpie.
>> M A G P I E Magpie.
>> Yeah.
Thank you so much for having me. It's
been a pleasure speaking to each and
every one of you. I hope I've been able
to answer some questions clearly. Uh I
apologize if I haven't and I look
forward to seeing you guys again if ever
I have the chance, whether it be in the
restaurant or anybody else.
Sound good, guys? Thank you so much for
having me and once again, thank you for
taking time out of your day.